Guide to the British authors collection M0121
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
British authors collection
1840-1953
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M0121
2.5 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Scope and Content
Literary manuscripts and letters of writers of the British Commonwealth. Correspondence, literary manuscripts, commonplace books, autographs, and photographs.
Provenance
Various sources.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
- AIKEN, LUCY (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - To Miss Rogers, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
- AINSWORTH, WILLIAM HARRISON (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - To Joseph B[?], Apr. 15, 1880.; ALS, 2 pp.,
    Scope and Contents note
    No donor information available.
  - To George Cruikshank, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
    Found in The Tower of Senden.
  - From George Cruikshank, undated; ALS, 2 pp.,
- AIMA-TADEMA, LADY LAURA (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - To Miss Hecht, with env., Nov. 27, 1897; ALS, 2 pp.,
- BELLOC, HILAIRE (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - To Clifton Fadiman, Jan. 4, 1938.; TLS, 1 p.,
    Purchased from David Magee.
  - Cautionary Tale Jim, included with same
- BENNETT, ARNOLD (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - To W.W. Lange, with env., Feb. 15, 1922; TLS, 1 p.,
  - To Pinker, date not legible, [1910?].; ALS, 1 p.,
    Purchased from Ben Bloomfield.
- BINYON, LAURENCE (1869-1943) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - To James, Sept. 19, 1937.; ALS, 2pp.,
- BOTTOME, PHYLLIS (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - To Mrs. [Max] Sloss, May 8, 1938.; TLS, 1 p.,
- BRIDGES, ROBERT SEYMOUR (1844-1930) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Tract 21 of Society for Pure English, May 1925.; TMs, 15 pp.,
- BROOKE, JOCELYN (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - From Joe Ackerley, May 14, 1953; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From Walter Allen, June 26, 1953; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Walter Allen, July 17, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Sybil Balchen, Aug. 5, 1953.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From Elizabeth Bowen, Mar. 24, 1953.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Ian Brown, Apr. 27, 1953.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Joyce Cary, May 18, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Arthur Colden-Marshall, May 29, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Noel Coward, June 16, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Daniel George, May 15, 1953.; APCS, 1 p.,
  - From Rupert Hart-Davis, June 4, 1953.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Harold Hobson, May 18, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Phillip Hope-Wallace, June 19, [1953].; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Gerald Kelly, Apr. 30, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From Rosamond Lehman, May 13, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Beryl Lester, June 19, 1953.; TNS, 1 p., (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - From Rose Macaulay, May 2, 1953.; APCS, 1 p.,
  - From Compton Mackenzie, May 19, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From George Jean Nathan, May 9, 1953.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From P. H. Newby, May 1, May 11, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From George D. Painter, May 16, 1953.; TLS, 2 pp.,
  - From William Plomer, May 14, 1953.; ALS 2 pp.,
  - From Anthony Powell, May 11, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Victor Pitchett, May 7, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Alan Pryce-Jones, June 16, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From Anthony Powell Quennell, June 16, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From E. Sackville-West, May 27, 1953.; APCI, 1 p.,
  - From V. Sackville-West, May 27, 1953.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From William Sansam, undated; ANS, 1 p.,
  - From J.D. Scott, May 15, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From J.D. Scott, May 19, 1953.; TNS, 1 p.,
  - From Frank Swineton, May 22, 1953.; ALS, 1p.,
  - From Frank Swineton, May 29, 1953.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From Frank Swineton, June 26, 1953.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From Evelyn Waugh, PM, May 9, 1953.; TPC, 1 p.,
  - From Angus Wilson, May 5, 1953; APCS, 1 p.,
  - From unknown, n.d. [1953?]; 6 TLS,
- BROOKS, HAROLD (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - To Professor Briggs, Oct. 12, 1940.; ALS, 1 p.,
    Source: Dr. William D. Briggs (#1438)
- BROWNING, ELIZABETH BARRETT (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hans Wolfgang von Herwarth's German translation of Browning's Sonnets from the Portuguese, Aug. 17, 1923.; TMs, 46 pp.,
    Inscribed to B.T. Wheeler.
- BROWNING, ROBERT (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - To Miss [Irene] Hardy, Mar. 6, [18]89.
    Includes envelope and typescript.
    Gift of Irene Hardy. (#38)
  - To Aunt Nina [Anna Jameson], [8/28/1856].
  - To Paul Kegan, 5/12/[18]87.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To unknown, 5/12/[18]80.; ALS, 1 p.,
    Source: M.C. Sloss
- BYRNE, DONN (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - To Mr. Harold Davis, with envelope., 11/8/1921; TLS, 1 p.,
    Purchased from Albert Sperisen.
  - W. Weatherbee to Sergeant, 3/20/1944.; ALS, 8 pp.,
  - In Praise of Lady Margery Kytler, undated; AmsS, 41 pp., (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CARPENTER, EDWARD (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - To J. Burton, June 11, 19?; APCS, 1 p.,
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins. (#510)
  - To Walt Whitman, July 12, 1874.; TLcc, 2 pp.,
  - To Walt Whitman, Jan. 3, 1876; TLcc, 3 pp.,
  - To Walt Whitman, Dec. 19, 1877.; TLcc, 2 pp.,
  - To Walt Whitman, Mar. 16, 1882.; TLc, 1 p.,
  - To Walt Whitman, Oct. 23, 1885.; TLc, 2 pp.,
- CARY, JOYCE (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - To W. B. Ready, 11/1/1954.
- COLLINS, WILKIE (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - To Charles Eyre Pascoe, Nov. 9 1873.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Trubner and Co., Mar. 13, 1884.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - Six letters of William Wilkie Collins from the Charlotte Ashley Felton Memorial Library at Stanford University by J. Terry Bender, Nov. 22, 1957.; TMs with ALS insertions,
    Contains an introduction by J.T. Bender and the following letters by Wilkie Collins:
    - To publisher (name illegible), typescript included., July 3, 1875; ALS, 4 pp.,
    - To Trubner and Co., with typescript., Nov. 18, 1878; ALS, 4 pp.,
    - To Trubner and Co., with typescript., Nov. 19, 1878; ALS, 4 pp.,
    - To J.M. Russell, with typescript., Dec. 2, 1884; ALS, 2 pp.,
    - To Ally Sloper, with typescript., Feb. 23 1886; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - The Victims of Circumstance, undated; AMsS, 6 pp., (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photograph of Wilkie Collins, undated; 4 1/4" x 6"
- COMMONPLACE BOOK (Box 1, Folder 20)
  18th century commonplace book containing handwritten original poems and extracts; some written in French towards end, 156 pp.
  Gift of Margery Bailey.
- CONRAD, JOSEPH (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - To F. O'Brien, Aug. 30, 1821.; ALS, 2 pp.,
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins. (#485)
  - Her Captivity, AMs and TMs with hand corrections, undated; 26 pp.,
    No donor information available. (#408950)
- COOK, ELIZA (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - To Mr. Clay, June 11, 1960.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To William Morton, Nov. 13, 1948.; ALS, 4 pp.,
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins.
  - To unknown, Mar. 31, 1949.; ALS, 4 pp.,
  - To unknown, May 17, 1949.; ALS, 4 pp.,
  - To unknown, June 27, 1949.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To unknown, Sept. 3, 1949.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To unknown, June 6, 1954.; ALS, 4 pp.,
    Source: Mrs. K.F. Elkins
  - To unknown, Apr. 8, n.y.; ALS,
  - To unknown, with envelope., July 12, n.y.
- COPPARD, ALFRED EDGAR (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - To R. Addyes-Scott, Apr. 1, 1946.; ALS,
  - To R. Addyes-Scott, Apr. 10, 1946.; ALS,
  - To R. Addyes-Scott, Mar. 14, 1948.
  - To Charles O'Malley, 6/30/32.; ALS,
  - To Charles O'Malley, Aug. 30, 1932.; ALS,
  - To Charles O'Malley, Nov. 10, 1932.; ALS,
  - To Mr. [R]anson, Mar. 7, 1928.; ALS,
- COPPARD, ALFRED EDGAR (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Agatha, Amy and Ruth, and, Jan. 1, 1939 Feb. 2, 1939; 34 pp.
  - Amanda, undated; AMs, 28 pp.,
  - Cheese, Nov. 25, 1949. June 1940.; AMs, 22 pp.,
  - Dark-Eyed Lady, undated; AMs, 19 pp.,
  - Deep and Dirty, Sept. 21, 1947.; AMs, 3 pp.,
  - Fatnose, Preedy and Anna, undated; AMs, 9 pp.,
  - I Know a Bank, June 12, 1937.; AMs, 11 pp., (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - The Nameless One, Apr. 7, 1943.; AMs, 6 pp.,
  - Old Rascal, Nov. 4, 1934.; AMsS, 6 pp.,
  - Pastoral Sympathy, undated; AMs, 11 pp.,
  - The Ring of Trouble, undated; AMs, 27 pp.,
  - Song in a Quiet World, undated; TMs with hand corrections, 15 pp.,
  - Speaking Likeness, Sept. 6, 1935.; AMs, 10 pp.,
  - Start-up, [Mar. 1951].; AMs, 11 pp.,
- COWARD, NOEL (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - To Arnold Bennett, Nov. 26, 1924.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - From Arnold Bennett, Nov. 28, 1924.; TccL, 1 p.,
    Source: James Sandoe (#1125).
    SEE ALSO BROOKE, JOCELYN
- DANE, CLEMENCE (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - To James Sandoe, Jan. 27, 1937.; TLS, 1 p.,
    Source: James Sandoe (#947).
  - To unknown, undated; ACS (Christmas card), 1 p., with photo of C. Dane,
- DELAMARE, WALTER (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Dutch Cheese, undated; TMs with handwritten corrections, 4 folio pp.,
    Purchased from Anthony Newnham.
- DICKENS, CHARLES (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - To Mr. Cartwright, Feb. 28, 1855.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - From Frederick Crichton, Mar. 31, 1847.; ANS, 4 pp.,
  - To Frederick Crichton AN, 1850.; 1 p.,
  - To [Thomas Adolphus] Trollope, Includes typed copy, Mar. 24, 1870; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To unknown, undated; ALS fragment,
  - To Home Insurance co., New York, Coutts Co., London, regarding authenticity of a check written by Dickens, July 8, 1901.; 2 pp.,
    Check included and dated Sept. 11, 1860.
  - Photo of Dickens, undated; 2 1/4" x 3 3/8",
  - Sketch of Dickens by C.A. Berry, undated; 8" x 9 1/4",
    Gift of E. Compton.
  - Picture of Dickens, with a check signed by Dickens, and a Dickens centenary testimonial stamp., n.d. dated Apr. 18, 1861; 8" x 11", (Box 1, Folder 30)
    (Original frame removed).
    Source: Mrs. K. F. Elkins.
  - Sketch by George Cruikshank of Dickens, 4 3/4" x 7". (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - To W.F. Crichton, Apr. 1, 1847.; Als, 1 p.,
    General note
    NOTE: These two items were framed together. Frame later removed for preservation reasons.
  - (Pencilled note on frame reads Property of O. E. Crichton). 66 Santa Monica Way, San Francisco.
- DOBSON, AUSTIN (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - To Col. Pridsaux, Sept. 6, 1907.; ANS, 1 p.,
    Found in first edition of Austin Dobson's Selected Poems of Matthew Prior.
  - To Arthur Symons, Apr. 2, 1908.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To unknown, Jan. 20, [19]20.; ALS, 3 pp.,
    Purchased with To a Lyric Poet proof. Vendor's initials, Lxy.
  - To unknown, LS, handwritten, Feb. 5, 1920.; 2 pp.,
    Purchased with To a Lyric Poet proof.
  - To a Lyric Poet, proof of poem with handwritten corrections, Jan. 1920.; 1 p., (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - To a Lyric Poet, final proof of poem, Jan. 1920.; 1 p.,
    Purchased, vendor's initials Lxy.
  - With Pipe and Flute, MsS, handwritten in pencil, Found in An Anthology of Prose and Verse by Austin Dobson, first American edition., undated
  - Whitehall Ecologue, Oct. 31, 1899.; AMsS, 1 p.,
    Note on back reads: Edmund Gosse gave this ms. to J. C. Squire, July 31, 1922.
    At botom on back are initials Sxy.
- DODGSON, C. L. (aka Lewis Carroll) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - To Miss Dyer, July 8, 1894.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Mary, Apr. 12, 1873.; ALS, 4 pp.,
    Purchased from Goodspeed.
- DOUGLAS, NORMAN (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - To Richard Aldington, May 25, 1931.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Sept. 27, 1931.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Oct. 20, 1931.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Aug. 23, 1932.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Feb. 28, 1934.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Sept. 23, 1938.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Oct. 25, 1938.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Nov. 11, 1928.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Nov. 14, 1938.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, P.M., Nov. 25, 1938.; PCS 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Dec. 19, 1938.; ALS 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, Jan 13, 1939.; ALS 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, July 24, 1939.; ALS 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, undated; PC 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, undated; ALS 1 p.,
  - To Richard Aldington, undated; ALS 1 p.,
  - To Douglas Goldring, June 18, 1924.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Douggold [Douglas Goldring], Mar. 24, 1926.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Douglas Goldring, May 12, 1926.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Douglas Goldring, Apr. 28, 1944.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Dear Madam, Apr. 7, 1930.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - Poem in German, possibly in Douglas' hand, no title, undated; 2 pp., (Box 2, Folder 5)
- DOYLE, ARTHUR CONAN (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Receipt from the Psychic Book Shop, Library and Museum, in Doyle's hand, Mar. 26, 1927.
- DUFFIN, HENRY CHARLES (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - To Carl Weber, July 2, 1962.; ALS, 2 pp.,
    Transferred to Special Collections.
- FIELDS, JAMES T. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - From C.E.S. Chambers to unknown, concerning Fields, Mar. 1932.; ANS. 1 p.,
    Found in Annie Fields', A Shelf of Old Books.
  - The Dead, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
- FLECKER, JAMES ELROY (1884-1915) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - To C.R. Haines, L (hand copied by C.R. Haines), Dec. 11, [1915].; 2 pp.,
    Note on envelope reads: one of Flecker's very last letters: he died a week or two later. Poverty obliged me to sell the original of this letter. May the author forgive me.
  - From Mrs. Helle Flecker to C.R. Haines, Oct. 1, 1916.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Mrs. Helle Flecker to C.R. Haines, Feb. 2, [1917].; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Mrs. Helle Flecker to C.R. Haines, Feb. 4, 1918.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - From Mrs. Helle Flecker to C.R. Haines, Jan 9, 1923.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - From Mrs. Helle Flecker to C.R. Haines, Dec. 18, 1930.; ALS, 2 pp.,
- GALE, NORMAN (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - To George S. Lockwood, Feb. 27, 1903.; ALS, 3 pp.
  - To George S. Lockwood, P.M., Apr. 23, 1903.; ALS, 1 p.
- GARNETT, RICHARD (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - To Mr. Colles, Apr. 4, 1900.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Mr. Colles, Nov. 7, 1903.; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Mr. Colles, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
    Source: Levintritt gift. Found in Twilight of the Gods by Richard Garnett.
- GISSING, GEORGE (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - To [Miss Hamel], May 23, 1895.; ALS, 2pp.,
    (Removed from Gissing's In the Year of the Jubilee; London: 1894.)
  - To Nelly [his sister Ellen], July 30, 1889.; ALS, 4 pp.,
    Typescript of letter included, 2 pp. No donor information available.
- GOSSE, EDMUND (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - To Phillip Guedella, TL with handwritten lines at bottom, May 5, 1928.; 1 p.,
    Found in Life and Letters of Evan Charteris by Edmund Gosse.
- GRAHAM, R. B. CUNNINGHAM (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - To T.J. Cobden-Sanderson, Oct. 30, 1906.; ALS, 4 pp.,
- GREGORY, LADY A. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - to Margaret Stor, undated; ANS, 1 p.,
- HARLAND, ALINE (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - To Mr. Stedman, May 21, 1894.; ALS, 6 pp.,
    Includes typescript of this letter, 2 pp., 2 copies.
- HAWKINS, ANTHONY HOPE (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - To unknown, undated; ANS, 1 p.,
- HENLEY, WILLIAM ERNEST (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - To Mr. Watts, Mar. 26, 1883.; ALS, 4 pp.,
- HEWLETT, MAURICE (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - To Henry Davray, Mar. 27, 1901.; ALS, 2 pp.,
- HILTON, JAMES (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - To Mrs. M.D. Sloss, Nov. 23, 1940.; TLS, 1 p.,
- HOUSMAN, A.E. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - To Grant Richards, typescripts of letters
    (For location of see letter at front of folder).
    originals see letter at front of folder.)
    - Aug 2, 1917
    - May 15, 1919
    - Aug. 21, 1920
    - Jan 5, 1921
    - Sept. 27, 1921
    - Apr. 3, 1922
    - Apr. 22, 1922
    - May 9, 1922
    - May 22, 1922
    - July 8, 1922
    - July 12, 1922
    - Mar. 3, 1925
    - Feb 3, 1926.
    - Jan 17, 1928.
    - Jan 19, 1928.
    - Apr. 24, 1928.
    - June 25, 1928.
    - Jan 30, 1929.
    - Feb. 5, 1930.
  - Photos of title pages from various books of poems and some photos of poems, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    no donor information available.
- HOWITT, MRS. MARY (BOTHAM) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - To W. Shubert, Jan 2, n.y.; ALS, 2 pp.,
    Source: Mrs. K. F. Elkins
- HUNT, LEIGH (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - To unknown, fragment with sketches on back, undated; ALS 2 pp.,
    Initials Yxy in bottom left corner (no price)
- JOYCE, JAMES (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript., Oct. 10, 1923; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Oct. 12, 1923; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Dec. 18, 1923.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Jan. 19, 1924.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Feb. 4, 1924.; ANS 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Feb. 14, 1924.; ANS 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript and envelope., Mar. 16, 1924; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript., Mar. 24, 1924; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript., Apr. 24, 1924; ALS, 1p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with env., May 21, 1924; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Jan 18, 1925.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Jan 26, 1925.; AC, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Jan 27, 1925.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, fragment, Apr. 5, 1925.; ALS, 2 pp 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript and env., Apr. 13, 1925; ALS, 3 pp.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Dec. 5, 1925.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Lily Bollach, May 2, 1926.; ANS, 1 p., (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - To Lily Bollach, with env., June 7, 1926; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with env., June 29, 1926; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Nov. 29, 1926.; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, Dec. 24, 1926.; ACS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, undated; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript., n.d; ALS, 1p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript., n.d; ALS, 1p.,
  - To Lily Bollach, with typescript and explanatory note., ALS, 1p.
  - To M. Davray, with typescripts in English and French., Mar. 16, 1920; ALS (in French), 2 pp., (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - To M. Davray, with typescripts in English and French. Original in possession of Anthony Harwood., Aug. 11, 1920; photocopy of ALS (in French), 1 p.,
  - To Ford Maddox Ford, with typescripts., Mar. 6, 1924; ANS, 1 p.,
  - To Mlle. Guillermet, with typescripts in English and French, and explanatory notes., Apr. 5, 1918; ALS (in French), 2 pp.,
  - To Forest Reid, with typescripts., May 10, 1917; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Forest Reid, with typescripts., July 13, 1917; ALS, 1 p.,
  - To Forest Reid, Aug. 1, 1918
  - To James Stephens, with typescripts., May 7, 1932; ALS, 3 pp., (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - To James Stephens, with typescript and env., Mar. 21, 1933; LS, 2pp.,
  - To M. Suares, with env., dated Aug. 20, 1920.; ALS (in French), 2 pp.,
  - Stuart Gilbert to Jacob Schwartz, Jan. 3, 1949.; ALS, 2 pp., (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Stuart Gilbert to Stanton Picher, Sept. 9, 1956.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Stuart Gilbert to Stanton Picher, Sept. 22, 1956.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Henry Levin to Quentin Keynes, Oct. 6, 1947.; TLS, 1 p.,
  - Jacob Schwartz to Stanton Picher, Jan. 1, 1949.; LS, 1 p.,
  - James Joyce Correspondence, article by Patricia Hutchins published in Encounter, Aug. 1956. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Gift of Stanton Picher.
- KAVANAGH, PATRICK (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Burial Service, undated; AMs, 1 p.,
  - Ethical, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Field Stone, undated; AMs, 1 p.,
  - The Irony of it, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - The Lady, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Last Lap, undated; AMs, 1 p.,
  - Listen, plus typescript., n.d.; AMs, 1 p.,
  - Monoghan Hills, undated; AMs, 1 p.,
  - Nora MacDonald, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Old Soldier, undated; AMsS, 2 pp.,
  - Plough, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Plough-Horses, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Ploughman, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - The Poet, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - The Poplars, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Primrose, undated; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Sanctity, undated; AMs, 1 p.,
  - Street Corner Christ, July 30, 1938.; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - To Anna Quinn, July, 1938.; AMsS, 1 p.,
  - Winter Sunset, undated; AMsS, 1p.,
    Purchased from Bertram Rota, Ltd.
- KENYON, FREDERICK (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - To T.J. Cobden-Sanderson, Jun. 16, 1920.; ALS, 2 pp.,
- KINGSTON, WILLIAM HENRY GILES (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Commonplace book, 1844-48.; AMs, 88 pp.,
    Contains miscellaneous collection of folk tales, verses, anecdotes, copies of naval reports, etc.
    Purchased from Frank Hollings (#506).
- KIPLING, RUDYARD (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - From Mrs. M.C. Sloss, July 8, 1935.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss, July 9, 1935.; TNS, 1 p.,
- LANE, MARGARET (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - To A. J. Symons, July 21, 1937.; ALS, 4 pp.,
    Found in At the Last Island, by Margaret Lane.
- LANG, ANDREW (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lucretius, Inscribed to Rev. Geoffrey Martin. Epistolary essay later published with other essays as a book, undated; AMsS, 17 pp.,
  - Letters on Literature, 1889.
    Purchased from James F. Drake (?)
- LEVER, CHARLES (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - To Mr. [Glashen?], undated; ALS, 2 pp.,
- LOCKE, WILIAM JOHN (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - To Mr. Horsburgh, Jan. 4, 1911.; ALS, 1 p.,
- MACAULAY, LORD T. B. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - To H.S. Randall, May 23, 1857; TL, 2 pp., 2 copies.
- MACDONOGH, PATRICK (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - To Mr. Chichester, with env., Nov. 14, 1941; ALS, 4 pp.,
  - To Chickie, [Chichester], Jan. 9, 1945.; ALS, 2 pp.,
  - The Vestal Fire, undated; AMs, 1 p.,
- MACFALL, HALDANE (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Beware the German's Peace, Feb. 15, 1918.; AMsS, 88 pp.,
    Source: William Wreden (#3507)
- MACHEN, ARTHUR (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - To Henry Savage, May 24, 1912.; TL Proof, 1 p.,
    (#404733)
- MACKENZIE, SIR COMPTON (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Carnival, AMs fragment, undated; 16 folio pp.,
  - Poetry and the Modern Novel, A paper read before the Potts Club, Mar. 28, 1912.; AMs, 18 folio pp., (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Seven Ages of Woman, undated; TMs with hand corrections, 237 pp., (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sinister Street, undated; AMs fragment, 6 pp., (Box 3, Folder 5)
- MAHONEY, FRANCIS SYLVESTER (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - To unknown (addressee illegible), undated; ANS 1 p.,
- MANSFIELD, KATHERINE (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 2 pp.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], undated; TL, 2 pp.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], [May 1921].; TL, 2 pp.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], [May 1918].; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Ottoline [Lady Ottoline Morrell], [Aug. 26, 1922].; TL, 1 p.,
    Original letters in M 147. No donor information available
  - To Dan Rider, with env., Nov. 16, 1917; ALS, 2 pp., (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Purchased from Emily Driscoll.
  - To Mr. [J. L. Squire], Dec. 1, 1920.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. [J. L. Squire], May 10, 1921.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. [J. L. Squire], May 12, 1921.; TL, 1 p.,
  - To Mr. [J. L. Squire], July 10, 1921.; TL, 1 p.,
    Purchased from Raphael King.
  - Enna Blake, published in The High School Reporter, 1898.; TMs, 1 p., (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Gift of G. N. Morris (#1487).
  - A Happy Christmas Eve, published in The High School Reporter, 1899.; 1 p.,
    Gift of G.N. Morris (#1488).
  - Reminiscences and Recollections, by Harold Beauchamp (KM's father), Chapter on Kate Mansfield, TMs fragment, 21 pp.
  - To Stanislaw Wyspianski, Jan. 1910.; TMs, 1 p.,
    (#1661)
  - Untitled TMs, 1903.; 3 pp.,
    Gift of G.N. Morris.
  - By the Sea, undated; TMs w/ handwritten corrections, 2 pp., (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Leves Amores, undated; TMs w/ handwritten corrections, 2 pp.,
  - Summer in Winter, undated; TMS with handwritten corrections, 2 pp.,
  - Vignette, undated; TMs with handwritten corrections, 3 pp.,
  - Westminster Cathedral, undated; TMs with handwritten corrections, 3 pp.,
    Addressed to Vere Bartrich Baker.
- MARRYAT, CAPT. FREDERICK (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - To Lady Morgan, P.M. 1832. (PR 4977 P5 1836), ALS, 2 pp.
- MARTIN, SIR THEODORE (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - To Thomas F. Bayard, Apr. 19, 1895.; ALS, 2 p pp.,
- MASEFIELD, JOHN (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - White Slave Traffic, Apr 24, [19?].; TL to the editor of The Times,
    Gift of Craig Palmer.
- MAYHEW, HENRY (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - To Mr. Tinsley, Jun. 3, 1868.; ALS, 2 pp.,
- MERES, FRANCIS (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Two ms. notebooks about Meres and his works, author unknown, undated
    Sloss gift (?)
- MEYNELL, ALICE CHRISTIANA GERTRUDE (THOMPSON) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - To Ladies, with env., Oct. 29, 1914; ALS, 2 pp.,
- MILES, SUSAN (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - To Katherine Mansfield, undated; TL published in The New English Weekly, 1 p.,
- MOORE, GEORGE (Box 3, Folder 18)